Hello English learners. Welcome back
to English Pod. My name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today we're bringing you the
eighth part of our dramatic romantic love
story. I'm sorry I love you. That's right
we're coming close to the end of this
story aren't we? Yeah we're coming
close to the end and we still have a lot of
interesting things going on so I wonder
what's going to happen. Well I can tell
you that today's lesson involves this word
which we'll hear in vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret-y preview. So today
we're just going to look at this
one word spy. A spy. A spy. All right so
we probably know famous spies like James
Bond or Austin Powers. Right so basically
it's a person who is secretly trying to
get information. About a government
or maybe a business. Right so that's a spy.
Now the verb. Two spy. Same thing right?
To spy on someone. Just spy on a company.
Yep. So why are we talking spies
and spying here in English Pod?
Why don't we find out by
listening to our dialogue?
Veronica Veronica Veronica are you okay?
Stephen what's going on? Who were those
guys? I didn't know you have a gun. What's
going on? I will come clean as soon as
we get to safety okay. For
now you have to trust me please
I would never do anything to
hurt you. Stephen I okay run!
I haven't been completely honest
with you Veronica I'm sorry I'm not a
fireman I'm not even
from the United States.
I'm a spy for the
Indian government.
What? Why didn't you tell me before?
What are you doing here? When I was a young
boy I used to play cricket with my father
back in my hometown of Hyderabad. He
was a peaceful town and my father was a
renowned chemist. One day he was approached
by members of the CIA claiming that
my father had made the discovery of the
millennium in his small lab back at the
university where he taught biochemistry.
I never saw him again. I vowed to
discover the whereabouts of my father and
consequently joined the
Indian intelligence bureau.
What does that have to do
with those men shooting at us?
Most importantly why did
you lie to me? I'm sorry I
wasn't supposed to meet you. I wasn't
supposed to fall in love with you but you
have to believe me when I tell
you that what I feel for you is real.
I can't believe this.
Why are all these things
happening to me? I
can't take it anymore let
me out of the car. All right so Stephen
is not even American. He's an Indian spy.
He's not even a firefighter. Well there
you go. Oh my god. Any surprises on this
love story. It gets deeper and deeper.
Well why don't we take a look at some of
a vocabulary that was used in this great
story in language takeaway. Language
takeaway. Well here we've got a lot of
language that you can use when you need
to be honest about something. We're
going to look at six phrases here. Now the
first one, Stephen says he needs to
come clean. Come clean. Come clean.
Right so basically he needs to tell the
truth. He needs to confess. Confess right?
About something that he maybe wasn't
truthful about in the past. Yeah maybe he
had a secret or maybe he lied about
something. So now he's coming clean.
Very good. So he comes clean and he tells
the story about his childhood and he says
his father was a renowned chemist.
Renowned. Renowned. Okay so if you are a
renowned chemist. You're very famous and
well respected. So you can use that with
people with places. A renowned restaurant.
Okay so very popular. Very well known.
Yeah we also hear it's commonly
like this. A world renowned chemist.
A world renowned restaurant. So not only
popular locally but the whole world knows
about. Very good. All right and so he
continues with his story and he says he
was approached by
members of the CIA.
Approached. To be
approached by. Okay so if I am
approached by somebody from the CIA.
What does that mean? Well they they come to
talk to you about something really
important. Okay so the verb to approach
someone can mean get
close to. Right to walk
up to them or
something like that. Right
but it also carries this this meaning of
coming to talk to you about something.
Something important. Something very
important. Yeah so for example I can say my
boss approached me this morning to talk
about an important pay raise. Ooh like you.
Or maybe Jim approached me to ask if I
know if his wife is cheating on him or not.
Wow all right so that's how you
would use this verb approach someone.
Now let's move on to the next word. So he
was approached by members of the CIA and
they were claiming something about
his father. That's right so to claim claim
something. To claim something. All right
so basically when you're claiming something
you are saying that it's true. Right it
might not be true but we don't know. Yeah
so for example he claims he makes
four million dollars a year. Okay or Bob
claims that he saw UFO. We can't prove
it if it's true or not but that's what
they're saying is true. Yep so Stephen's
father disappeared and well he vowed to
discover where he was. So Stephen
vowed to find his father. Wow to vow.
So this verb to vow means to make a strong
promise right. Yes and we use it also in
marriage right. Wedding vows. Wedding vows
which are basically promises. So if you
vow something you make a very strong
promise. Yes it's very very bad if you
break a vow. Oh really? What happens?
I don't know probably thunder strikes you
you die. All right so don't break
your vows. Yeah. And the last word on
language takeaway today. The whereabouts.
The whereabouts. The whereabouts of his
father. So the whereabouts is the location.
The location. Kind of unknown
location right? Right. I think this is a
great word for us to listen to some more
examples. Example one the
police don't have any information
on the whereabouts of the murderer. Example
two. Currently the whereabouts of the
president are unknown. Example three.
You live in Toronto too? Whereabouts do you
live? All right so whereabouts perfect you
can use it for location unknown location.
All right so some great words now I
want to move on to some phrases that
we heard in the dialogue and let's look
at those now in fluency builder. Fluency
builder. All right I'm fluency builder
today we have four great phrases and let's
start with the first one. What's going on?
So Veronica asks what's going on?
Steven what's going on? Basically
what's happening right? What's happening?
What's what's the situation? Yeah now
another interesting thing is that among
friends you could use this phrase to say
hey how are you? How are you? How's it
going right? So you can say hey Erica
what's going on? And it all depends on your
your tone of voice. So when you want to
know how that person is hey Marco what's
going on? Right but if you're angry or
maybe something strange is happening
you're like hey what's going on here?
Yes so your voice falls. Right now let's
take a look at our next phrase and
this one is very very useful especially if
you've lied. Yes so Steven says I
haven't been completely honest with you. I
haven't been completely honest with you.
I haven't been completely honest with you.
So that means he hasn't been telling
the whole truth. Right pretty easy
to understand but I think its use is
interesting here. Right you might
use it to kind of soften up the person to
confess something. Right so when you're
ready to come clean about a secret you
have or allow you told this is a great
way to prepare your listener. Right
know what I haven't been completely honest
with you. Yeah moving on to our third
phrase. So the CIA claimed that Steven's
father had made the discovery of the
millennium. The discovery
of the millennium.
Discovery of the
millennium. Okay let's
break this down. Millennium. Millennium is
a thousand years. Right so the discovery of
the millennium is the best most important
discovery in the past thousand years.
Right so now we can change it a little bit
and say the invention of the millennium.
Or even the party
of the millennium.
Exactly so it
doesn't necessarily
have to be the most important of the last
one thousand years. But it means it was
pretty good. It was pretty good. Very
important. Yeah. Hey you can also say the
discovery of the decade right. Of the
decade of the century. Yep. Of the year.
Yep. And now let's take a look at
our last phrase. So Steven confessed he
came clean. He told her everything but
he said he wasn't supposed to fall in love
with her. I wasn't supposed to.
I wasn't supposed to fall in love with you.
All right so let's look at this
phrase. I wasn't supposed to.
It's an interesting one. It's sort of like
a cross between I didn't need to and I
shouldn't have done. Right now let's
look at some examples. I wasn't supposed to
come to work today. All right so you didn't
need to. It wasn't necessary. All right so
maybe it was your annual vacation day
but you came into work anyway. Or maybe it
was a holiday and I came to work anyways.
So the plan was not for you to come
to work. Right. So in this case we're
saying it wasn't necessary. Or it wasn't
planned. Our plan. Yeah. Now let's look at
it the other way when you shouldn't. Okay
Marco I wasn't supposed to tell you
this but. Okay. So now in this case you
shouldn't be telling me this. You shouldn't
tell me the secret. Yep. But you're
going to anyways. Yes. Off air. So I
wasn't supposed to. In this case it means I
shouldn't. All right so I'm really great
language here. Now I think it would help
us to hear it one more
time in the dialogue.
Veronica Veronica Veronica are you okay?
Stephen what's going on? Who were
those guys? I didn't know you have a gun.
What's going on? I will come clean as
soon as we get to safety okay.
For now you have to trust me please I would
never do anything to hurt you. Stephen I
okay run. I haven't been completely honest
with you Veronica. I'm sorry. I'm not a
fireman. I'm not even from the United
States. I'm a spy for the Indian government.
What? Why didn't you tell me before?
What are you doing here? When I
was a young boy I used to play cricket
with my father back in my hometown of
Hyderabad. He was a peaceful town and my
father was a renowned chemist. One day
he was approached by members of the CIA
claiming that my father had made the
discovery of the millennium in his small
lab back at the university where he taught
biochemistry and never saw him again.
I vowed to discover the whereabouts
of my father and consequently joined the
Indian intelligence bureau. What does
that have to do with those men shooting at
us? Most importantly why did you lie to me?
I'm sorry. I wasn't supposed to meet
you. I wasn't supposed to fall in love
with you but you have to believe me when
I tell you that what I feel for you
is real. I can't believe this. Why are
all these things happening to me? I can't
take it anymore. Let me out of the car.
Okay great so now we're getting close to
the end of this series so what's going to
happen? Maybe Veronica's also a spy.
Oh my god I don't think I can handle that.
All right so we really
need your suggestions.
We need your ideas.
We want to know
how you think the series ends
or how you would want it to end.
Do you want it to
be a happy ending?
Or a tragedy? Or maybe
action-filled ending?
All right well we got two
lessons left in this series
so visit our website
at EnglishPod.
com and leave your suggestions.
All right guys we'll see you
guys there and until next time. Goodbye!